# ANDREW VAN

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**└** (416) 930 - 7930 | **⋉** andrew.van1@live.com | **(** avan3 | **(** avan3 )

### SUMMARY

Solutions driven software engineer adept at contributing in a highly collaborative and fast-paced work environment. Proven experience developing web applications primarily using Angular, Typescript, CSS, and Java. Able to apply good knowledge and experience towards software development life cycle.

# **SKILLS**

**Programming:** TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Python

Web Development: Angular, RxJS, NgRx, HTML, CSS, Spring Boot, Storybook, Node.JS, React

Database Technology: MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Redis, GraphQL

Testing: Junit, Mockito, Karma, Jasmine, Cypress

Tools: VS Code, IntelliJ, GitLab, Bitbucket, GitHub, Jira, Jenkins, DotCMS,

Microsoft Azure, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes

# **EXPERIENCE**

IT Developer III

Toronto, ON

TD Bank Dec 2022 – Present

- Completed integration of API with existing application, achieving an estimated annual cost reduction of \$1M
- Developed prepopulating logic for PDF forms resulting in reduction of time spent completing forms by 1000 hours annually
- Developed modernization of web application used regularly in TD branches including refactor of frontend logic to backend, and integration with internal TD applications
- Developed features with accessibility in accordance to WCAG 2.1 standards
- Provided prompt solutions and proactive troubleshooting support to quickly resolve subtle and complex issues leading to increased client satisfaction

Software Engineer Toronto, ON

Architech Jan 2020 – Aug 2022

- Developed navigation features increasing ease of navigation throughout pages in the application and between modules in the application
- Built RESTful API endpoints that served data to the Angular front-end according to client's requirements
- Refactored code into reusable components and migrated code for reusability between application modules
- Collaborated closely with diverse team of software & DevOps engineers, product owners, project managers and clients in an Agile environment

# **EDUCATION** -

Computer Programming & Analysis, Diploma

Sept 2018 - Apr 2020

Seneca College, Cumulative GPA: 4.0/4.0 **Honours Bachelor of Science**, Degree

Sept 2009 - Apr 2013

University of Toronto St. George

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals - AZ-900